<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><TEI:TEI xmlns:TEI="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><TEI:teiHeader/><TEI:text><TEI:body><body xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><div id="d39873e38326"><note id="d39873e38621" place="end"><ab id="d39873e38622"><foreign xml:lang="en"><hi rend="underline">Gladiator, dying</hi>, is a most valuable monument of ancient sculpture. This man, when he had<lb id="d39873e38627" n="1"/>
                received t mortal stroke, is particularly careful, <hi rend="underline">ut procumbat honeste</hi>, that he might fall<lb id="d39873e38632" n="2"/>
                gracefully; he is seated in a reclining posture on the ground, &amp; has just strength sufficient<lb id="d39873e38634" n="3"/>
                to support himself on his right arm; &amp; in his expiring moments, it is plainly seen that he<lb id="d39873e38636" n="4"/>
                does not abandon himself to grief &amp; dejection, but is solicitous to maintain that firmness<lb id="d39873e38639" n="5"/>
                of aspect, which the gladiators valued themselves on preserving in this season of distress, &amp;<lb id="d39873e38641" n="6"/>
                that attitude wh. they had learned of the masters o defence. He fears not death, nor seems to<lb id="d39873e38643" n="7"/>
                betray any tokens o fear by his countentance, nor to shed one tear: "quis mediocris gladiator<lb id="d39873e38645" n="8"/>
                ingemuit, quis vultum mutavit usquam, quis non modo stitit, verum etiam decubuit<lb id="d39873e38647" n="9"/>
                turpiter", says Cicero, in that part of his Tusculan, where he is describing t astonishing firm-<lb id="d39873e38649" n="10"/>
                ness o these persons. We see, in this instance, notwithstanding his remaining strength, that<lb id="d39873e38652" n="11"/>
                he has but a moment to live, &amp; we view him with attention, that we may see him expire<lb id="d39873e38654" n="12"/>
                &amp; fall: thus the ancients knew how to animate marble &amp; to give it almost every ex-<lb id="d39873e38656" n="13"/>
                pression of life.</foreign> Rus's Cyclop.-<lb id="d39873e38659" n="14"/></ab></note><note id="d39873e38660" place="end"><ab id="d39873e38661"><foreign xml:lang="en"><hi rend="underline">Hermaphrodite</hi> Two beautiful statues in a recumbent position are in t Florentine Gallery. A small<lb id="d39873e38666" n="15"/>
                hermaphrodite statue is seen in t villa Albani, a very fine one at Paris, &amp; there is another in an obscene<lb id="d39873e38668" n="16"/>
                attitude,</foreign><lb id="d39873e38670" n="17"/><note id="d39873e38671" place="end">der stehende Hermaphrodit in der Villa Borghese.<lb id="d39873e38673" n="18"/></note><foreign xml:lang="en">pointing out that it partakes of t two sexes. All these are males in t external appearance<lb id="d39873e38676" n="19"/>
                o their generative organs, females in t form o t breast, in t features, in t elegance o t <del>features</del> figure,<lb id="d39873e38681" n="20"/>
                &amp; t softness o t contours. They exhibit an attempt to form a more perfect being, by uniting<lb id="d39873e38683" n="21"/>
                together t peculiar excellencies of t male &amp; female, without attending very particularly to t<lb id="d39873e38685" n="22"/>
                genital organs.- cod. <hi rend="underline">Generation</hi>, by Lawrence. - Winkelmann. 4o. 1. p. 364.<lb id="d39873e38691" n="23"/></foreign></ab></note><note id="d39873e38692" place="end"><ab id="d39873e38693"><hi rend="underline">Niobe</hi>. <foreign xml:lang="la">Ultima restabat, quam toto corpore mater,<lb id="d39873e38699" n="24"/>
                Tota veste tegens, unam, minimamque relinque;<lb id="d39873e38701" n="25"/>
                De multis minimam posco, clamavit, et unam!</foreign> Ovid.<lb id="d39873e38704" n="26"/></ab></note><note id="d39873e38705" place="end"><ab id="d39873e38706"><foreign xml:lang="en">The Statue and the verses form an excellent commentary upon each other.<lb id="d39873e38709" n="27"/>
                
                    "The verse and sculpture bore an equal part,<lb id="d39873e38711" n="28"/>
                    And art reflected images to art."</foreign> Matthews's Diary. 1. p. 50.<lb id="d39873e38714" n="29"/></ab></note></div></body><TEI:pb/></TEI:body></TEI:text></TEI:TEI>